Linklab (Olsson Hall - Second Floor), University of Virginia, Charlottesville, VA

□ (434) 466-7628 | **S**sb5ce@virginia.edu | **□** Sonia2016 | **□** sonia-baee

Profile

I am starting my third year as a Ph.D. student at the University of Virginia in the Department of System and Information Engineering, working with Dr. Laura Barnes. In our research, we use mobile sensing technology, and the associated contextual data in mental health domain to deliver just-in-time prompts to individuals to promote right actions for their situation. Currently, I am working on prediction of drop-out from the study by using individual behavior pattern. We would like to give the right treatment in the right time to each participant. We are planning to use digital coaching to address idiosyncratic physical, behavioral and psychological processes of individual users to optimize utilization, compliance, efficacy, and maintenance.

Education_

University of Virginia

Charlottesville, Virginia

PHD IN SYSTEM AND INFORMATION ENGINEERING - ADVISOR: LAURA BARNES

August 2017 - Present

- · Project: Conversational agent in mental health
- · GPA: 3.98

Amirkabir University of Technology

Tehran, Iran

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE - ADVISOR: S. MEHDI HASHEMI

2011 - 2013

- Thesis: Improve Patient's Satisfactions by using Electronic Medical Records and Building Management Systems (sensors)
- GPA: 18.26/20 (Thesis grade: 19.5/20)

Amirkabir University of Technology

Tehran, Iran

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE - ADVISOR: S. MEHDI HASHEMI

2007 - 2011

- Thesis: A New Urban Train Boarding/Alighting Strategy Proposition Using Passengers Micro-Movement Modeling
- GPA: 18/20 (Thesis grade: 20/20)

Experience

Graduate Research Assistant

August 2017 - PRESENT

UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA

- · Digital Coaching: how to use conversational agent to optimize utilization, compliance, efficacy, and maintenance of mental health
- Managing Anxiety: how does cognitive behavior modification change anxious person's behavior?
- · Attrition: how to detect a participant is planning to leave the study at right time
- · Mental-health framework: how to detect person's loneliness based on their text communication
- MindTrail project: Data analysis for finding patterns of user's behavior and response
- Emotion regulation: how anxious people regulate their emotion based on location and EMA

Researcher Sept 2015 - July 2017

KNOWLEDGE REPRESENTATION LAB - TEXAS TECH UNIVERSITY

· ALM: creating a compiler for modular action language

2011 - 2014 **Software Developer**

ITS - AMIRKABIR UNIVERSITY OF TECHONOLGY

- · Business Intelligent: how to recommend the product to the user based on their history of orders
- Intelligent Parking: develop a system to show vacant spots in parking for reservation

Researcher 2011 - 2013

NORC - AMIRKABIR UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY

- Energy Management in Hospital: Resource allocation
- Decision Support System: dynamic resource allocation for assigning clinicians to patients

Teaching

Teaching Assistant, Amirkabir University of Technology

Fall 2011

CS 1316104: PRINCIPLE OF COMPUTER 2

- Developed the assignments, final project and grade them
- · Held office hours

Teaching Assistant, Amirkabir University of Technology

Spring 2011

CS 1316004: PRINCIPLE OF COMPUTER 1

- · Developed the assignments, final project and grade them
- · Held office hours

CS 1316163: PRINCIPLE OF SOFTWARE DESIGN

- Developed some of the assignments, final project and grade them
- Developed course instructions and course materials

Guest lecturer, Texas Tech University

CS 2413: DATA STRUCTURE

• Teaching different types of search algorithms

Fall 2016

Publications.

SocialText: A Framework for Understanding the Relationship Between Digital

2019 Communication Patterns and Mental Health., Mendu, S., Boukhechba, M., Baglione, A., Baee, S., Wu, C., Barnes, L., 2019, January. In 2019 IEEE 13th International Conference on Semantic Computing (ICSC) (pp. 428-433). IEEE.

Web-based Interpretation Training for Anxiety: Testing Target Engagement and

2019 **Effectiveness for a Treatment Seeking Community Sample,** Ji, J.L., Baee, S., Zhang, D., Meyer, J., Barnes, L.E., Teachman, B., UNDER REVIEW

Do I feel better or do I think I feel better? The effectiveness of emotion regulation strategies

depends on how effectiveness is measured, Daniel, K., Baee, S., Barnes, L.E., Teachman, B., UNDER REVIEW

What is effective? Assessing different aspects of emotion regulation effectiveness in daily

life., Daniel, K., Baee, S., Barnes, L.E., Teachman, B., Regulating Emotions Effectively: New Approaches to Understanding Effects of Time, Person, and Development. Symposium to be presented at the Association for Psychological Science Annual Convention, Washington, D.C.

A social cognitive theory-based framework for monitoring medication adherence applied to endocrine therapy in breast cancer survivors., Boukhechba, M., Baee, S., Nobles, A.L.,

2018 Gong, J., Wells, K. and Barnes, L.E., 2018, March. In IEEE-EMBS International Conference on Biomedical and Health Informatics. IEEE-EMBS International Conference on Biomedical and Health Informatics (Vol. 2018, p. 275). NIH Public Access.

Passenger Boarding/Alighting Management in Urban Rail Transportation, Baee, Sonia,

2012 Eshghi, F., and Hashemi, S. M.,2012 JOINT RAIL CONFERENCEPhiladelphia, Pennsylvania, USA, April 17-19

Skills_

Programming Python, Java, R, C/C++, SQL programming

Web Angular.Js, Javascript, CSS

Research Interest

- Conversational agent
- Recommendation System
- Text Mining
- · Reinforcement Learning

- Mental Health
- Mobile Sensing
- Personal Health care Informatics
- Mathematics Modeling and Simulating

Honors & Awards

- 2019 **Distinguished Graduate Student Award**, University of Virginia
- 2018 NSF Travel Awards, IEEE EMBS
- 2017 **Distinguished Fellowship,** one of the most prestigious fellowships offered to engineering students at the University of Virginia.
- Presidential Fellowship, this fellowship was funded in part by the Ed and Linda Whitacre
 Graduate Fellowship Endowment in Texas Tech University
- 2015 **Scholarship Recipient**, to attend CRA-W (Computing Research Association) Grad Cohort Workshop.
- Presidential Fellowship, this fellowship was funded in part by the Ed and Linda Whitacre
 Graduate Fellowship Endowment in Texas Tech University
- 2013 **2nd Place**, among Computer Science Artificial Intelligent M.S. students, Amirkabir University of Technology.
- ${\bf 2011} \qquad {\bf Distinguished~BSc~student~award~,~with~honorary~acceptance~for~the~MSc~program~}$
- 2010 **1st Place**, among Computer Science and Mathematic B.S. students, Amirkabir University of Technology.

_



2019	REU mentor , Creating personalized-content for anxious people in the study, University of
	Virginia
7111X_7111Y	Academic and Industry Chair, Link Lab Student Committee on Culture and Livability,
	University of Virginia
2018-2019	Grad SWE board , webmaster of Women Engineers organization, University of Virginia
2018	REU mentor , Detecting mental health from social media data, University of Virginia
2018	NSBE UVA recruiter , recruiting prospective students at the 2018 National Society of Black
	Engineers (NSBE) National Convention, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania
2018	SWE UVA recruiter , recruit at the 2018 SWE National Convention, Minneapolis, Minnesota
2016	REU , Declarative Approaches to Knowledge Intensive Applications, Texas Tech Department of
	Computer Science

3